准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
失踪的床垫
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
又要迟到了
I'm really late again
多半得开除我了吧
Maybe they'll finally fire me
什么
What?
锁上了
Locked?
不可能有这种事
This isn't happening
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
太可怕了
The horror--
关
一言难尽
it's unspeakable
看不出来吗  章鱼哥
Don't you see, Squidward?
关门了
It's closed
蟹堡王关门了
The Krusty Krab is closed
你是说我白起床了吗
You mean I got out of bed for nothing?
门锁上了
The doors are locked--
门锁上了  我们却在外面
the doors are locked and we are on the outside
门外汉
Outsiders
怎么办才好  章鱼哥
What are we going to do, Squidward?
蟹黄堡在里面多么寂寞
There are Krabby Patties inside all alone
站一边去  小子
Just stand aside, lad
我来开锁
and let me unlock the door
蟹老板  你来了
Mr. Krabs, you're here
天啊  蟹老板
Gosh, Mr. Krabs
我们担心你有啥三长两短
we were worried something might have happened to you
世间顶级美食差点就不复存在了
when the world would've been deprived
of the greatest food known to man
你害我钥匙掉了
You made me drop me keys
也给点私人空间吧
Give me some space, lad
螃蟹就不能有点空间吗
Can't a crab get a little space?
对不起  蟹老板
I'm sorry, Mr. Krabs
太狠了
Harsh
我的老背
Me back
你伤着了吗  蟹老板
Are you hurt, Mr. Krabs?
没  我就单纯忍痛弯个腰
No, I'm just doubled over in pain
强忍泪水不哭出来
fighting back tears in me eyes
最近就流行这种舞蹈
because it's a new dance craze
好  还以为你伤着了
Good, I thought you were hurt
我就是伤着了  白痴
I am hurt, you idiot
抱歉吼你了  小子
I'm sorry I snapped at you, laddie
只是我的背真的疼死了
It's just me back is killing me
都怪我的高低不平旧床垫
It's me old lumpy mattress--
睡上去就好像睡破珊瑚一样
it's like trying to sleep on broken coral
都快把我给逼疯了
I'm going out of me mind
我的老背
Me back
蟹老板真可怜
Poor Mr. Krabs
该怎么办  章鱼哥
What are we going to do, Squidward?
办什么办
Why do anything?
我就喜欢蟹老板现在这样
I like the new Mr. Krabs--
更爱吼你了
he yells at you more
我没开玩笑  章鱼哥
I'm serious, Squidward
我也没
So am I
应该要给他买个新床垫
We should get him a new mattress
给他来个惊喜
and surprise him with it
这样我们就再也不会晚上班了
Then we'll never have to be late to work again
什么
What?
你是想要我把血汗钱
You want me to spend my hard-earned money
花在比我还富的小气老板身上是吧
on my richer-than-me skinflint boss?
免谈
No, thank you
没关系  章鱼哥
That's okay, Squidward
你等下一定会接受这提议的
You'll warm up to the idea
谢谢你跟我来  派大星
Thanks for coming with me, Patrick
没事的  兄弟
No problem, buddy
我老想去床垫专卖店了
I always wanted to go to a mattress store
床垫专卖店
从来没见过这么多床垫
I've never seen so many mattresses
对啊
Yeah
你觉得店里有几张床垫
How many do you think there are?
十张
Ten
不错
Cool
还有不少呢
There's plenty more than that
试睡一下吧
Try 'em out--
找找有没有看中的
find one you like
蟹堡王
你们俩白痴在干什么
What are you morons doing?
给蟹老板做贺卡
Making a card for Mr. Krabs
跟新买的床垫一起送过去
To go with his new mattress
睡个安稳觉
懂了  原来你是想拍老板马屁
I see, you're just kissing up to the boss
显得我态度很难看
to make me look bad
完全忍不了了
Well, I won't stand for it
贺卡给我
Give me that card
想耍小聪明赢过我是吧
Trying to outsmart me, will you?
好了  我给咱仨都签了名
There, I signed it for all of us
你都没出钱
You didn't even help pay
没事
That's okay
蟹老板高兴就好
As long as Mr. Krabs is happy
我的老背
Me back
反正肯定又睡不着
Well, here goes another useless attempt
但也只能睡我这高低不平大床垫了
to sleep on me mountainous, lumpy mattress
不对劲
That's queer--
床垫感觉特别舒服
me mattress seems strangely cozy
就跟
and
黄油
butter
好像
like
惊喜
Surprise
世界末日了
Armageddon
什么
What?
你们
You?
你们来我卧室干什么
What in a blue-eyed scallop are you doing in me bedroom?
我们发现
We noticed
你睡在高低不平旧床垫特别难受
how miserable you were on your lumpy, old mattress
所以我就提议给你买个新的
So I suggested we get you a new one
不是你提议的吗
I thought it was your idea
所以我旧床垫哪去了
So, where's me old mattress then?
放心  蟹老板
Don't worry, Mr. Krabs
我也亲自处理好了
I took care of that personally, too
已经拖去垃圾场了
I had it hauled away to the dump
我
All
所有
my
钱都在那床垫里
money was in that mattress
什么
What?
你就没听说过银行吗
Haven't you ever heard of a bank?
没有
No
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
不要
No
我们还要给你送贺卡
And we got you a card
里面有钱吗
Is there money in it?
没有
Nope
急诊
严重吗  医生
Is it serious, Doctor?
蟹老板没事吧
Will Mr. Krabs be all right?
蟹老板得了金钱昏迷症
Mr. Krabs is in a cash-coma
只有钱物归原主了才能脱离生命危险
Only the return of his money can save his life
都怪海绵宝宝
It was SpongeBob's fault
都是他提议要给蟹老板买床垫
Getting Mr. Krabs a new mattress was his idea
我就知道
I knew it
别急
Not so fast
这贺卡上面写着
This card says
都是我提议的
"This was all my idea
爱你的章鱼哥
Love, Squidward"
要是蟹老板没康复
If Mr. Krabs doesn't pull through
你就得去坐牢
you're going to jail
新床垫你买的  海绵宝宝
You did this, SquarePants
要是你没去垃圾场找回蟹老板的床垫
If you don't get Mr. Krabs' mattress back from the dump
我就要宰
I am going to mur
再亲自帮你
Help you do it myself
他真的很在乎
He really does care
垃圾场
好一个垃圾场
What a dump
关
一定得进去  章鱼哥
We've got to get in there, Squidward
蟹老板就指望我们了
Mr. Krabs is counting on us
海绵宝宝  那边那个是要找的床垫吧
SpongeBob, isn't that the mattress over there?
太好了  派大星
Terrific, Patrick
你找到了
you found it
什么
What?
在哪
Where?
我看看
Let me see
就在那边  章鱼哥
Over there, Squidward
在那个特大看门虫底下
underneath that really big guard worm
意料之中
That figures
不会吧
Oh, no
太可怕了
This is horrible
怎么了  医生
What is it, Doctor?
这位没医保
This man has no insurance
绝对住不起这间病房
He'll never be able to afford this room
还真是  护士
You're right, nurse
把病人赶到走廊去  快
Extract the patient to the hallway, stat
汽水
零食
那个确定就是蟹老板的床垫了
Well, that's Mr. Krabs' mattress all right
一起夺回来吧
Let's go get it
好  下面是计划
Okay, here's the plan
你们两个静悄悄地潜进去
You two quietly go in there
从看门虫底下挪走床垫
remove the mattress out from under the guard worm
不能  把虫子吵醒
without "waking the worm"
为什么
Why not?
吵醒就不礼貌了  派大星
Because that would be rude, Patrick
垃圾场的虫子最凶了
And nothing's meaner than a junkyard worm
它会生吃了你们
He'll eat you alive
先等一下
Wait a minute
那你要干什么
What are you going to do?
我有最重要的任务在身
I've got the most important job
得要放哨保安全
I'm going to keep watch to make sure it's safe
那就谢了  兄弟
Gee, thanks, buddy
不客气
My pleasure
快行动起来
Now let's get a move on
是不是很美啊  派大星
Isn't it beautiful, Patrick?
坐这里风景尽收眼底
You can see everything from up here
你们俩白痴干什么
What are you morons doing?
派大星  这边好像可以看到我们家
Hey, Patrick, I think I can see our houses from here
在哪
Where?
我看不到
I can't see 'em
再来一遍
Let's do it again
你们俩白痴干什么了
What did you idiots do?
章鱼哥  你进去干什么
Squidward, what are you doing in there?
你应该放哨的
You were supposed to keep watch
对啊  而且你还吵醒看门虫了
Yeah, and you woke up the guard worm, too
我才没有
I didn't do it
是你们吵醒
You blockheads woke
的
the
虫子
worm
医生
Doctor?
是的  医生
Yes, Doctor
有关你的病人  医生
Regarding your patient, Doctor
我有如下结论
I have come to this conclusion
是的  请说
Yes, go on
必须特地把他挪开
We have to surgically remove him out
别让他挡了糖果贩卖机
from in front of the candy machine
零食
这样我才买得到坚果棒
so I can get to the Nutty-Nut Bar
好的
Of course
护士
Nurse
交给我
I'm on it
虫饵呼叫寻垫者
Worm Bait to Retriever
虫饵呼叫寻垫者  我们进来了
Worm Bait to Retriever, we're in
完毕
Out
寻垫者呼叫虫饵
Retriever to Worm Bait
待在里面  别出去
stay in, don't go out
明白
Understood
完毕
Out
出 去
不对  待着
No, in
完毕
Out
明白
Understood
完毕
Out
你们在垃圾场另一头是吧
You're on the far side of the dump, right?
是的
Affirmative
很好  那就大吵大闹
Good, then make lots of noise
引走看门虫  让它离开床垫
to draw the guard worm away from the mattress
方便我寻回床垫
so I can retrieve it
了解
Affirmative
完毕
Out
怪不得他会自称寻垫者
That's why he calls himself the Retriever
我们为什么要叫虫饵
Why are we called Worm Bait?
不知道
I don't know
对了
Oh, yeah
真是好办法  派大星
Great idea, Patrick
我的完美计划太顺利了
And my perfect plan falls into place
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
怎么了  派大星
Yes, Patrick?
我好像知道我们代号为什么叫虫饵了
I think I know why our code name is Worm Bait
虫子乖
Nice worm
虫子温柔点
Good, kind, gentle worm
海绵宝宝  它喜欢你的木头勺子
Oh, SpongeBob, he likes your wooden spoon
还真是  派大星
I think you're right, Patrick
看看它玩不玩捡棍子
See if he plays catch
好
Okay
看好棍子
See the stick, boy
快去捡
Go get it, boy
前方安全
Coast is clear
章鱼哥  你真是个天才
Squiddy, you are a genius
怎么
What the?
我正好很需要木头勺子
I needed a wooden spoon
放屁股口袋保管  省得弄坏
I'll just keep it safe from harm in my back pocket
现在来搬床垫
And now for the mattress
早该猜到的
I should have guessed
不好意思  医生
Excuse me, Doctor
船骸管理员  有什么事
Administrator Flotsam, what can I do for you?
我注意到你的病人蟹老板
It has come to my attention that your patient, Mr. Krabs
在门口的人行道昏迷不醒
is out on the front sidewalk
是的
Yes
没错
Yes, he is
你想什么乱七八糟的
What were you thinking, man?
这可是做生意
We're trying to run a business here
不能把病人留在人行道上
We can't leave patients on the sidewalk
放心
Not to worry
护士
Nurse
交给我
I'm on it
你们两个怎么磨蹭这么久
All right, you two, hat's the holdup?
感觉自己很傻
We feel silly
真是的  要为蟹老板着想
Come on, do it for old man Krabs
好吧
Okay
能再解释一遍计划吗  章鱼哥
Can you explain the plan again, Squidward?
好  但首先
Sure, but first
这个古龙水擦一下
put on this cologne
牛排酱
Steak sauce?
好  你们两个扮成了精切牛排
Okay, so you two are dressed as choice cuts
快进去喊一声  不给糖就捣蛋
You go in there and yell "Trick or treat"
虫子会发现自己忘了囤万圣节糖果
The worm will realize
he forgot to stock up on Halloween candy
就会去补货  然后床垫到手
he'll leave to buy some, then we take the mattress
古龙水给我
Give me that cologne
快进去
Now get in there
万圣节快乐  章鱼哥
Happy Halloween, Squidward
这次绝对伤不到我
I am not going to get hurt this time
怎么
What the?
那不是蟹老板吗
Isn't that Mr. Krabs?
那条看门虫好像不太高兴的样子
That guard worm doesn't look very happy
快跑  蟹老板
Run, Mr. Krabs
清醒过来赶紧跑
Run like you're not in a coma
是
It's
我的钱
me money
钱啊
Oh, money
我发誓再也不丢下你了
I promise I'll never leave you alone again
蟹老板
Hey, Mr. Krabs
不对  蟹老板
No, Mr. Krabs
是我们
it's us
不给糖就捣蛋
Trick or treat
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
都没认出你
I didn't recognize you
话说你们干嘛要打扮成肉排
Say, why are you two dressed as meat?
不只是肉排
Not just meat--
是精切牛排
we're choice cuts
对吧  章鱼哥
Right, Squidward?
我投降
I give up
走开
Get away
老板打官司
分镜总监
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
海之霸
又过了一个不眠夜
And so passes another sleepless night
连个蟹黄堡都偷不到  烦得我睡不着
haunted by my inability
to steal even a single Krabby Patty
可能今天就能偷到吧
Maybe today will be the day
谢谢你的客气话  电脑老婆
Thank you for your patronizing words, computer wife
你有没有计划
Do you even have a plan?
出口
要什么计划
Plan, schman--
我直接临场发挥
I'm going to wing it
情况还能糟到哪去
What's the worst thing that could happen?
蟹堡王
进来了
I'm in
太简单了
That was easy
也许今天
Maybe today is the day
我就能偷到蟹黄堡的秘密配方了
I'm going to steal the Krabby Patty formula
小心  痞老板
Careful, Plankton
这边地板刚拖过
I just mopped there
看看你  痞老板
Look at you, Plankton
你又万分悲惨地摔在地上失败了
Once again you've fallen flat on your back
没能偷到我的秘方
in another pathetic attempt to steal me formula
尽管你试了又试
Though you tried and tried
结果我的美味秘方还是到不了你嘴边
you haven't had the smallest nibble
of my delicious formula
以后也不可能
And you never will
明知自己都这么废了  怎么睡得着觉
How do you sleep at night
knowing you're a complete failure?
应该放个小心地滑警告牌的
There really should be a "Wet Floor" sign
对啊  要是那边滑倒的是我
Yeah, if that were me who slipped
早就去把老螃蟹告个倾家荡产了
I'd sue old man Krabs for all he's got
蟹黄堡秘方是不是也能告过来
Does that include the Krabby Patty formula?
那当然了
Of course
疼死我了
The pain
手臂还有腿都没知觉了
I can't feel my arms and legs
好像都摔断了
I think they're broken
一定要打官司赔偿我的痛苦和折磨
I'll have to sue for my pain and suffering
打官司
Sue?
好像伤得很重
That looks bad
小家伙真可怜
Poor little man
先等一下
Hold up a second
痞老板
Plankton
这种小事还是别闹到法庭上吧
we don't need to
drag this little incident into court, do we?
那个嘛
Well
你把蟹黄堡秘方交给我
if you transfer the Krabby Patty formula to me
我就不计较你讨人厌的过失了
I'll forget your gross negligence
无赖
Scoundrel
想要我秘方
You'll have my formula
先等我没命了再说
when you pry it from me lifeless claws
法庭见了  老螃蟹
See you in court, Krabs
我是说
I mean
疼死我了
The pain
简直疼得要命啊
The deep frying pain
我废了啊
I'm in a blue ruin
完了啊
I'm doomed
放心  蟹老板
Don't worry, Mr. Krabs
我会不惜一切代价
I will do whatever it takes
保护蟹黄堡秘方
to keep the Krusty Krab formula
绝不让它落入痞老板的魔掌
from getting into Plankton's evil hands
我真正需要的是好律师
What I really need is a good lawyer
你好  有谁说律师吗
Hello, did somebody say "lawyer"?
理查德臭鱼烂虾
律师
我是理查德臭鱼烂虾  一名律师
Richard A Bottomfeeder, Attorney At Law
无意间注意到了刚刚的卑鄙情节
I couldn't help but notice that despicable display
那
So, uh
请律师要花多少钱
how much is this going to cost me?
其实官司打输不收钱
Actually, I won't charge you a dime unless we win
说实话  应该倒打一耙
In fact, I think we should counter sue
把痞老板所有财产都告过来
for everything Plankton owns
这种事情常有吗
Does that happen a lot?
没有  一般是银的
No, they're usually silver
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs?
怎么了  小子
What is it, lad?
请你先听听我的证词
I thought you might want to hear my testimony
等你叫我出庭作证  我就会上去念
for when you call me as a character witness?
我一直都在排练呢
I've been rehearsing it
其实吧  海绵宝宝
Actually, SpongeBob
不用你来提供证词
we won't be needing any testimony from you
感觉你比较会
Why, you'd be more of a
惹麻烦  没多大用
of a liability than an asset
可是我
But I
快走吧
Now, run along--
赶紧去准备庆功了
make things shipshape for my victory celebration
得早点去法庭
I've got to get to the courthouse early
免费停船位就那么几个
There's only a few free parking places
官司一定胜券在握
This is going to be a slam dunk
不会吧
Oh, no
蟹老板的律师
Mr. Krabs's lawyer
跟我说话啊
Speak to me
摔疼我了
Wracked with pain
没法动
Can't move
可蟹老板的官司怎么办
But what about Mr. Krabs's case?
看来你得亲自解决了  小子
Looks like you're going to have to handle this one, son
可我会
But I'm a
惹麻烦
a liability
打赢官司的所有材料
Everything you need to win
都在这箱子里
is in this here case
真的吗
Really?
所有材料
Everything?
只缺一件西装
Everything but a suit
西装
A suit
不知道西装得上哪找
Wonder where I could get a suit
法院
再给你最后一次机会
I'll give you one last chance
交出秘方就撤诉
I'll drop the charges if you give me the formula
休想  你这小东西
Never, you little whelp
我的小胳膊
My wittle arm
什么
What?
我根本就没对他动爪子
No, I didn't lay a claw on him
我另一条胳膊
My other arm
他骗人
He's lying
保持法庭肃静
Court will come to order
挠背大法官主审
The Honorable Judge Tickleback presiding
蟹老板  你的律师呢
Mr. Krabs, where is your attorney?
我不知道他在哪
I don't know where he could be
我来了
Here I am
感谢你入场  请问你是
Thank you for joining us, Mister
海绵律师宝宝  法官大人
SpongeBob Lawyerpants, Your Honor
你来干什么  海绵宝宝
What are you doing here, SpongeBob?
你的律师呢
Your lawyer, uh
工作期间摔倒了
fell down on the job
不过请蟹老板放心
But don't worry, Mr. Krabs
一切都在我掌控之中
I have everything under control
全都
It's, uh
在这里面
all in here
真的吗
Really?
没错  就在
Yup, right in
里面
here
有问题吗
Is there a problem?
你的律师没给我密码
Your lawyer didn't give me the combination
原告是否准备好继续
Is the plaintiff ready to proceed?
是  法官大人
Yes, Your Honor
我尽量
I'll try
我身为原生动物  并不总会饱受折磨
I wasn't always the tortured shell of a protozoa
可是今天却在你们面前痛苦挣扎
that writhes in pain before you today
我
I
曾是个逍遥自在的单细胞生物
was a vibrant carefree, happy-go-lucky single cell
打起精神来  小子
Pull yourself together, boy
然后就在那个命途多舛的日子
Then came the fateful day
我心中毫无恶意  去了那个死亡陷阱
that I paid an innocent visit to the deathtrap
也就是蟹堡王
known as the Krusty Krab
怎么样了  小子
How's it coming, lad?
放心  蟹老板
Don't worry, Mr. Krabs
我在开了
I'm on the case
正当我进了方才所说的那家店之时
Upon entering said establishment
周围没有告示  也毫无预兆
I found myself without any warning
我滑了一跤  摔在坚硬无情的地板上
slipping and finally falling
onto a hard, unforgiving floor
而地上还故意倒了滩罪孽深重的液体
that had been intentionally
covered with a vicious fluid
投弹
Bombs away
你闹完了没
Are you quite finished?
刚说到哪了
Where was I?
对了
Oh, yeah
最糟糕的就是
But the worst part is
我本来梦想要跑完马拉松的
my dreams of completing a marathon
而且还跟我奶奶发过誓的
like I promised my old Grammy
结果全都破灭了
have been dashed
对不起  奶奶
I'm sorry, Gram-Gram
对不起
Sorry
谢谢大家关心
Thank you for your kind attention
白痴
Suckers
被告是否进行开场陈述
Does the defense have an opening statement?
是  法官大人
Yes, Your Honor
奶奶好可怜
Poor Gram-Gram
蟹老板  你认得这个东西吗
Mr. Krabs, can you identify this item?
小心地滑
是小心地滑警告牌
It's a "Wet Floor" sign
你有吗
Do you own one?
那个
Well
我没有
No, I don't
陪审团
不对  你们不懂
No, no, you don't understand
我得做出艰难的商业决定
I had to make some tough business decisions
这牌子好像
and the sign seemed
很没必要
superfluous
没有其他问题了
No more questions
请你举证  律师宝宝
Your witness, Mr. Lawyerpants
今天之内举证  宝宝先生
Sometime today, Mr. Pants
陪审团的女士先生及庭上  请听我说
May it please the court
ladies and gentlemen of the jury
大众称我的委托人小气  吝啬
my client has been called "cheap," "miserly,"
而且长期抠门
and "chronically tightfisted"
但倘若他真如原告所言那般小气
But if he were as cheap as the prosecution claims he is
那他真的会眼睁睁的坐着
would he be able to sit there quietly
看我拿出一块钱  扔进搅拌机里吗
while I took out a dollar and dropped it in the blender?
轻搅
重搅
狂搅
不要
No
老爸来救你了
Daddy's got you
老爸来了
Daddy's here
一点胶水  一点胶带
A little glue, a little tape--
你就能康复了
you'll be right as rain
老爸没忘记你
Daddy didn't forget you
被告是否申请证人出庭作证
Does the defense have any witness to call?
是  法官大人
Yes, Your Honor
被告申请
Defense calls
章鱼哥出庭作证
Squidward to the stand
章鱼哥  忠诚的员工
Squidward, a loyal employee
你是
Mister, uh
章鱼哥先生吧
Squidward is it?
大众称我的委托人小气
My client has been called "cheap"
你是否认可以上荒谬的陈述
Would you agree with that ludicrous statement?
是
Yes
什么
What?
请允许我换个方式提问
Allow me to rephrase the question
你能否向庭上
Can you tell the court
举例说明蟹老板有何大方表现
of some instance of Mr. Krabs's generosity in any way?
不能
Nope
我能走了吗
Can I go now?
三年好不容易放一天假
One day off in three years
非得过来作证吗
and I have to spend it testifying?
一定要
Must
打开
open
箱子
case
原来  就是你害地板变滑的吧
So, it was you who made the floor slippery, wasn't it?
从实招来
Answer the question
要我提醒你  你可是宣过誓的吗
Need I remind you you are under oath?
死到临头了
I'm doomed
还是别开箱子了  小子
You may as well give up on that case, me boy
我都已经完蛋了
my goose is cooked
蟹老板  你惊到我了
Mr. Krabs, I'm surprised at you
就算事态不乐观也不能放弃
We can't give up just because things look bleak
打赢官司得靠真心
This trial will be won by what's in your heart
而不是这破箱子里的小玩意
not what's in this dumb old case
打开了
It's open
就
It's
只是律师的午餐
It's just his lunch
是这样吗
Or is it?
被告申请痞老板出庭
Defense calls Plankton to the stand
你那天为什么要进蟹堡王
Why did you go into the Krusty Krab that day?
就  跟我从前的好朋友蟹老板打招呼
To, you know, say hello to my once-good-friend, Mr. Krabs
怎么了
What?
你确定自己不是想去偷
Are you sure it wasn't to make off
这种东西吗
with one of these?
逮到了
Gotcha
你该不会是过去偷秘方的吧
Weren't you there to steal the formula
好让你做出最香最好吃的三明治
of the most delicious, sweet-smelling sandwich
全裤头村都远近闻名
known to Bikini Bottom?
蟹黄堡
Krabby Patty
受不了了
I can't take it
给我
Give me
好耶
Yippee
终于是我的了
Finally it's mine
我拿走了
I'll take that
不要
No
痞老板  生命中最甜美的胜利再度
Once again, Plankton, the sweetest of life's joys
离你而去了
has eluded your grasp
不要
No
陪审团是否已作出裁决
Has the jury reached a verdict?
是  法官大人
We have, Your Honor
我们裁决被告
We find the defendant
无罪
not guilty
但是很小气
But he is cheap
谢谢  海绵宝宝
Thank you, SpongeBob
我一开始不让你帮忙  真有点糊涂了
I was foolish not to accept
your help from the beginning
没事的  蟹老板
That's okay, Mr. Krabs
我给你做了礼物
I made you a present
给我的礼物吗
A present for me?
闭上眼睛  伸出手
Close your eyes and hold out your hand
小心地滑
是小心地滑警告牌
It's a "Wet Floor" sign
我亲自做的
I made it myself
还算可以
Well, it'll do
毕竟免费
After all, it's free